Violeta Lopez-Bumgartner

Creative & UX Design Technologist // Technical Artist // Prototyper

info@violetforest.com https://violetforest.com linkedin.com/in/violet-forest

Working with VR, AR, & CV since 2016, with prior experience as a front-end developer from 2015 to 2018.

Industry experience in the US & Europe as a Technical Artist & UX Design Technologist.

Clients include Meta, Snap, Volkswagen, Porsche, Patagonia, & Skechers.

Experience

Meta — Technical Artist, Present - July 2023

Collaborating with C++ and Typescript engineers to build Meta's proprietary game engine.

Creating USD pipelines to convert Maya FBX assets to USD using Python.

Ingestion for VFX, FBX, gITF, OBJ, animation and skybox for Horizon Worlds.

Prototyped MR experience for Hackathon.

Creating and manipulating assets using Maya, Blender, PopcornFX, and Perforce.

Ado-Ato Pictures — Technical Artist, 2023

Prototyped segmentation tests and feature detection tests with Niantic Lightship AR in Unity.

Created shaders with ShaderGraph for a Niantic Lightship AR app.

Facilitated pipeline between 3D artist assets and Unity integration for AR.

Floodplains.xyz — Technical Artist + Unity Developer, 2023 - 2022

Developed and shipped a game for WebGL and Meta Quest 2 based on client's designs.

Prototyped and shipped WebXR version for VR.

Snap Lens Creator — Prototyper + Technical Artist, 2021 - 2022

Commissioned by Snap to create an AR experience for the Spectacles AR glasses and mobile devices.

Commissioned by Snap to demo the Spectacles AR glasses at Augmented World Expo in Santa Clara.

Hicetnunc.xyz — React Developer, 2021

Prototyped and developed front-end features and fixed bugs in React JS.

Tracked github issues, wrote the github wiki, and provided technical support to users for blockchain transactions.

Tweag I/0 — 3-month fellowship with engineers (Paris), 2021

Concepted, developed & user-tested a bluetooth Android app that uses hand-tracking to control a robotic prosthesis.

 ${\tt ^*Google \, Feature: \, https://developers.googleblog.com/2021/05/control-your-mirru-prosthesis-with-mediapipe-hand-tracking.html}$

Volkswagen Future Center Europe — UX Design Technologist (Berlin), 2020-2018

Collaborated with UX designers to identify users needs & prototype features based on user feedback.

Designed & developed prototypes for features using facial recognition, pose recognition, and eye tracking.

Developed a mixed-reality experience in virtual reality for Porsche, using LeapMotion and HTC Vive.

Prototyped an in-car audio-reactive visualization using Unity's VFXGraph and ShaderGraph.

Presented designs, prototypes and concepts to stakeholders.

Unity C# Developer — Freelance | Next/Now Agency, Midwest Immersive, CanvasChicago, 2019-2017

Prototyped, developed, and shipped applications with computer vision features for AR mobile and webcam kiosks with Unity. HTC Vive, VRTK, ARFoundation, openCVforunity

Front-End Developer — Freelance | Someoddpilot, Studio 424, SOCIALDEVIANT, 2018-2015

 $Worked\ with\ various\ design\ studios\ developing\ \&\ deploying\ desktop/mobile\ landing\ pages\ and\ kiosks.$

NPM, SSH, javascript, Three.js, WebMidi, Google Maps API

Education

The School of the Art Institute of Chicago

Master of Fine Arts: Art + Technology, 2016 Creative Coding: openFrameworks, Processing, three.js

Florida International University

Bachelor of Arts in Art: Minor in Art History, 2012 Film Photography, Experimental video

Miami Dade College

Associate in Science: Graphic Internet Technology, 2009 E-commerce development, HTML/CSS/Javascript/PHP, Graphic Design & Typography

Personal Projects